<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech Blog - Hasitha Aravinda</title><link>https://hasithaa.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Tech Blog - Hasitha Aravinda</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hasithaa.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>&lt;i class="fab fa-github">&lt;/i> Ballerina-Platform</title><link>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/ballerina/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/ballerina/</guid><description>Ballerina.io
Ballerina Compiler Design and Implementation ballerina-lang
I&amp;rsquo;m currently leading the design and architecture of the Ballerina Language Compiler implementation. Before Ballerina became a fully-fledged general-purpose language, we experimented with DSL-like syntaxes, and I was a part of the compiler and runtime team from that time. After several years of dedicated development and design, we have successfully built a Ballerina Compiler that meets the needs of developers who want to write integrations.</description></item><item><title>&lt;i class="fa fa-server">&lt;/i> WSO2 Business Process Server</title><link>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/bps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/bps/</guid><description>WSO2 Business Process Server Carbon Business Process Product BPS (Archived)
WSO2 Business Process Server (BPS) was an easy-to-use, open-source business process server that executed business processes written using BPMN, WS-BPEL, and WS-HumanTasks standards. As a developer and release manager of this product, I had the opportunity to contribute to its development and add various features, including HumanTask Coordination, Caching layer, and multiple UX improvements. While the product is now deprecated, I&amp;rsquo;m always happy to answer any questions you may have about it.</description></item><item><title>&lt;i class="fa fa-server">&lt;/i> ODE - A WS-BPEL Engine</title><link>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/ode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/ode/</guid><description>ODE Apache ODE (Forked) Apache ODE (Retired)
This repository contains the WSO2 maintained fork of the retired Apache ODE project, which was a WS-BPEL compliant web services orchestration engine. As a developer on this project, I had the opportunity to work on its development and maintenance. While BPEL has less traction now and the parent project is retired, I&amp;rsquo;m always happy to answer any questions you may have about it.</description></item><item><title>&lt;i class="fa fa-server">&lt;/i> WSO2 Business Rules Server</title><link>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/brs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/brs/</guid><description>WSO2 Business Rules Server Product BRS (Archived)
WSO2 BRS was a lightweight and easy-to-use Open Source Business Rules Server that allowed business decisions to be exposed as secure and reliable web services and integrated with an organization&amp;rsquo;s application integration infrastructure. As a maintainer and release manager of this repository, I had the opportunity to contribute to its development and maintenance. However, the product is now deprecated.</description></item><item><title>&lt;i class="fab fa-github">&lt;/i> Java4BPEL</title><link>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/java4bpel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/java4bpel/</guid><description>Java4BPEL Extension java4bpel
Java4BPEL is an extension for Apache ODE and WSO2 BPS that I developed. It introduces a new BEPL extension activity that allows Java libraries to be invoked using BEPL. This extension activity enables the integration of Java code within the BPEL process flow, providing greater flexibility and customizability. I&amp;rsquo;m proud to have developed this extension and hope that it has proven useful for those using Apache ODE and WSO2 BPS.</description></item><item><title>&lt;i class="fa-solid fa-code">&lt;/i> MetCat</title><link>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/metcat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hasithaa.github.io/projects/metcat/</guid><description>metcat
The MetCat project was aimed at developing a metadata catalog that could be integrated with the Apache Airavata project. The project&amp;rsquo;s primary focus was on capturing metadata from workflows and assisting in scalable metadata management and user-defined queries. While the project is now deprecated, it was a valuable learning experience and an opportunity to contribute to the development of an important tool in the scientific community.</description></item><item><title>[Blog] Ballerina `setup-ballerina` Action</title><link>https://hasithaa.github.io/blog/2023/setup-ballerina/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hasithaa.github.io/blog/2023/setup-ballerina/</guid><description>This post was originally published on Dev Community and covers the usage of the new setup-ballerina GitHub Action.
&amp;quot;Simplify Ballerina Workflow on GitHub with setup-ballerina Action&amp;quot;. @ballerinalang #DEVCommunity https://t.co/NhxviW2DaQ
&amp;mdash; Hasitha Aravinda (@HasithaAravinda) February 20, 2023</description></item><item><title>[Video] Introduction to Ballerina - A Cloud Native Programing Language</title><link>https://hasithaa.github.io/blog/2022/meetup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hasithaa.github.io/blog/2022/meetup/</guid><description>Online Meetup This meetup was held on 2nd February 2022 and hosted by the CodeSeeker’s Endless Programming Languages meetup group. Watch the recording.</description></item><item><title>My Old Blog</title><link>https://hasithaa.github.io/blog/old/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:25:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hasithaa.github.io/blog/old/</guid><description>Are Looking for my older Blog? It is here, https://tryitnw.blogspot.com/.</description></item></channel></rss>